<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Trino swap file</title><link href="/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="/feeds/all-en.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>/</id><updated>2019-04-01T00:00:01+02:00</updated><entry><title>German phrases</title><link href="/deutsch-phrases.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-04-01T00:00:01+02:00</published><updated>2019-04-01T00:00:01+02:00</updated><author><name>Omar Gutiérrez</name></author><id>tag:None,2019-04-01:/deutsch-phrases.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Some notes to help me to learn German.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I will compile, &lt;strong&gt;nach und nach&lt;/strong&gt;, useful (and not so useful) phrases in German
that I will master &lt;em&gt;nach und nach&lt;/em&gt; to improve my skills in that language.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am also jotting down its equivalents in Spanish:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Daily phrases&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;em&gt;Deutsch&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Español&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;em&gt;Hast du Kleingeld dabei?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;¿Tienes (tú) cambio?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;em&gt;Haben Sie Kleingeld dabei?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;¿Tiene (usted) cambio?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;em&gt;Ist dieser Platz (noch) verfügbar?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;¿Está (todavía) disponible este lugar?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;em&gt;Sitzt hier (schon) jemand?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;¿Hay (ya) alguien sentado aquí?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Mottos&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;em&gt;Deutsch&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Español&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;em&gt;Es ist niemals zu spät&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Nunca es demasiado tarde&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;em&gt;Es ist OK, nicht OK zu sein&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Está bien no sentirse bien&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;More phrases&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;em&gt;Deutsch&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Español&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;em&gt;Seit jeher&lt;/em&gt;...&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Desde siempre...&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;</content></entry><entry><title>The Parrot's Theorem</title><link href="/sidney.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-04-01T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2019-04-01T00:00:00+02:00</updated><author><name>Omar Gutiérrez</name></author><id>tag:None,2019-04-01:/sidney.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Review and summary of The Parrot's Theorem by Denis Guedj (still incomplete)&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;!--
Guedj wrote a joyful novel about the history of Maths, that is, a good
introduction to Maths.

## Chapter 1. A Bird in the Hand

**Max Liard** rescues a parrot that two fellows were attacking.

## Chapter 2. Seen and Not Seen

Mr. Ruche explains how **Thales** was able to realize

## Chapter 3. The Glass Pyramid

Mr. Ruche and Albert along with the kids go to the Louvre Museum, specifically,
to the Glass Pyramid.
--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am update this post from time to time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Chapter 4. The Rainforest Library.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mr. Ruche receives the crate of books that Grosrouvre sent him. The collection
is called the Rainforest Library!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mr. Ruche, Perrette, the twins, and Max discuss together how to classify the
"Rainforest Library." They agree to organize the crate of books into the next
categories: Geometry, Arithmetic, Algebra, Trigonometry, Probability,
Mechanics, Logic, and the New Maths!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Max visits a pet shop along with Sidney; he is looking for food for the parrot,
there, he sees an official notice stating that to have a pet in France this one
needs to have an official certificate. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He is told by a girl working there that Sidney is a valuable bird talker, an
Amazon blue. The boy has a bad feeling with the girl and quickly gets out of
the pet shop. After that, the girl calls someone giving details about Max and
Sidney!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Chapter 5. The Three Ages of Math.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mr. Ruche visits the library for several days, where he studies who were the
most important mathematicians and their contributions in different periods of
the history.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first day he compiles the list of mathematicians from Ancient Greece, from
700 BC to AD 700. The second day, he continues with the distinguished names in
the Arab world, from AD 800 to 1400. And finally, he finishes listing the
people of the Western world, from 1500 to 1900.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After that, he along with Perrette, start to classify the books in the crates,
one by one. And he realizes that, indeed, Grosrouvre was not exaggerating when
he said in the letter that was the world's best collection of books about
mathematics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Chapter 6. Friends and Enemies&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mr. Ruche receives an envelope from Brazil that informs him that Grosrouvre was
found dead; another letter is inside the pocket, it is directed to him and
written by Elgar. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Perrette reads the letter to Mr. Ruche. In the letter, Elgar tells him that he
solved two theorems and decided to keep them in secret. However, some people
with bad intentions was trying to know the solution of those theorems and were
behind him. He says goodbye.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mr. Ruche is sad because of his best friend.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He, Perrette and the boys (except Lea) discuss the content of the letter, and
they try to work out what happened with Elgar.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Chapter 7. The Numbers Game&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mr. Ruche examines the life of Pythagoras and his disciples, the so-called
&lt;em&gt;Pythagoreans&lt;/em&gt;, such as Hippasus, the leader of the initiated or
&lt;em&gt;acousmaticians&lt;/em&gt;; Hippocrates, who studied the crescents or lunes and was
thrown out of the Pythagorean school; Philolaus, the survivor of the fire
provoked by a rejected aspirant, Cylon. Philolaus was an astronomer. Also
Archytas, who was an engineer and is reputed to have made a mechanical bird,
Archytas also saved Plato from a tyrant called Denys. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After reading about Pythagoras, he along with Max and Sidney prepares a lecture
to explain to the rest other details about Pythagoras, such as the relationship
between musical notes and numbers, the Pythagoras's theorem, and how the
initiation was done in his school. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The aspirants to be his student were supposed to wait for five years in silence
behind a curtain.  Those who were waiting to see the master face to face were
called &lt;em&gt;exoterics&lt;/em&gt;, and the ones who achieved the honor were known as
&lt;em&gt;esoterics&lt;/em&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mr. Ruche says to the guys that they are worthy of being esoterics. Mr. Ruche
discusses with Perrette about Grosrouvre. She thinks that they should consider
the possibility that he is not dead. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, and because of Lea was insisting that she was starving, Mr. Ruche
suggests to go for an &lt;em&gt;all-nighter&lt;/em&gt; and Albert, who was there all the time,
wakes up and refuse to be an &lt;em&gt;esoteric&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Chapter 8. Just a Fraction&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mr. Ruche organizes a night school where he discusses the root of number two. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Perrette reflects on all the things that are happening since they received the
letter. Max is pouring the water from one vase into another, to help Sidney to
reach the water in the glass; she quickly realizes that the water will overflow
because she sums the ratio of water in each vase, Max gets impressed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Albert tells Max about the knowledge he has acquired of different cities in his
profession as a taxi driver, even when he has never been in those cities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The twins together work at the night and proof that there is not a fraction,
that, squared, could equal two. Perrette and Mr. Ruche are impressed; he
approves his evolution from acousmaticians to mathematicians.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Chapter 9. Night Boat to Alexandria&lt;/h2&gt;</content></entry></feed>