<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Trino swap file - self-growth</title><link href="/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="/feeds/self-growth.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>/</id><updated>2019-01-08T00:00:01+01:00</updated><entry><title>Slow and Steady</title><link href="/slow-and-steady.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-01-08T00:00:01+01:00</published><updated>2019-01-08T00:00:01+01:00</updated><author><name>Omar Gutiérrez</name></author><id>tag:None,2019-01-08:/slow-and-steady.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Ideas about the life after reaching 30 years!&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;!--
_The lights go out,_
_I am all alone, all_
_are buried in the snow._

_I_
_and it holds me,_
_and it never lets me go._

_I move slow and steady,_
_but I fell like a waterfall._

_Yeah, I move slow and steady,_
_past the ones that I used to know._

_And, I am never ready,_
_because I know_

gqap and `fo+=a`
--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is time to stop, and reflect. I arrived possibly to the half of the way, so,
it is a good moment to look back and see the many things that I have done
wrong, and the few things that I have done well. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is merely a personal reflection, I am making public, because, yep, the
people put its stuff in internet. Hopefully, will be useful for my niece in
some years, so, I dedicate these words to you Karol, some years in the future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am trying to put together the noise from last years, piece things together,
or as someone said, connect the points.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Mexico, the roots&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I dream, since the most inner of my hearth that Mexico will change, that a
new and different Mexico is possible. It is worth to dream about it. But
recently, I started to think, that maybe not, maybe Mexico will never change.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I did believe in the political project of the left, at this point, after some
time they (we) arrived to the power.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The PhD and Data Science&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For first time in my life I am not sure about the doctorate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is depressive to tell it, but I am not more in love with science as I was at
the beggining.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was not enjoying the path in too many stages; I became to Germany, waiting to 
learn&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;%This has caused me to doubt every single decision I’ve made over the past few years&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;%&lt;em&gt;Un día eres joven y al día siguiente estás reflexionando sobre la vida.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;% to say the least&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;% Thinking outside of the box&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;No te revientes reata, por que (no) es el último tirón.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;My health&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;% Put here the image of thirty zone&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is when you start to care about your health, about the future, about the
happiness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Loneliness and love&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During a lot of time, loneliness was not a problem, I truly enjoyed to be alone
in the highschool, I read a lot during that period.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have been alone most of time during these thirty years, at the middle of my
twenties, this became a horrible thing. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Happily, I still have few friends that helped me in hard moments, so, I am not
totally alone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Being the good and turning the other cheek does not work, at least not for me,
at least not in every case. Why is so hard to find real friends?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am feeling empty. &lt;em&gt;For me is too complicate (it is impossible) to forgive&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have been in love with Irasu and Miriam during the highschool, and Valeria during the highschool. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The thing with Irasu never worked, she hit me. With Miriam and Valeria
was different, I was not able to give the last step. Yes, I am a mother fucker.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don't give a shit to write the name of the girls, very likely they won't read this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And then, happened again, I fall in love during last year. I even
learned to ride a bike because of that, and that is interesting, because I
never tried to ride a bike after I fell down so badly when I was a kid. Once
again, as with Irasu, I was hitted. Even worse, I was swinged. As one song in
Spanish says: &lt;strong&gt;Ácabame de matar, pa' qué me dejas herido&lt;/strong&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;</content></entry></feed>